Now that the planning is done,
Artk planlama yaplr.
let's dive into the project and let's actually build this application.
Projeye girelim ve gerekte bu uygulamay oluturalm.
For this, I opened a brand new project created with create react app,
Florida'nn yaratcs yeniden eyleme uygulamasyla yaratlm yepyeni bir projeyi atm.
nothing has been changed here yet.
Burada henz bir ey deimedi.
Now in this project, I first of all want to enable css modules so that I can make sure that the css
imdi bu projede ncelikle CSS modllerini etkinletirmek istiyorum, bylece bir CSS
classes we create in a css file can be scoped to a specific component in our application so that
dosyasnda oluturduumuz snflardaki bu Cs'nin uygulamanzdaki belirli bir bileene kapsanabileceinden emin olacam,
they are not applied globally when we would accidentally reuse the same css class.
bylece Clovelly'ye uygulanmaz yanllkla ayn CSSA snfn tekrar kullanrsnz.
For that I need to eject the project
Bunun iin projeye yemek yemeliyim.
as you learned, so let's do that first.
rendiiniz gibi nce bunu yapalm.
Let's run npm run eject in the newly created project and this will now ask us if we really want to eject,
NPM run eject'i yeni oluturulan projede altralm ve imdi kontrol etmek isteyip istemediimiz sorulacak.
so I will confirm this with Y for yes, and now as you saw it before in the module where I showed you how
Bu yzden evet iin Y ile onaylayacam ve daha nce Seer'in modl olarak
to implement css module, you get access to the config in a config folder and there to the two
atma klasrne nasl eriileceini gsterdiim modlde grdm gibi, slak paket
webpack configuration files.
yaplandrma dosyalar nedeniyle iki tane var.
Now let's dive into the first of the two and search for the part where you have the css test
imdi ikisinin birincisine dalalm ve testi deerlendirmek zorunda olduunuz blm aratralm.
and the css loader. There as I showed you in the mentioned module, you have to add modules true to the options
A. S. s modlnde gsterdiim gibi s ykleyicisi var, bu ykleyicinin seeneklerine gerek modlleri
of that loader and add the localIdentName option to basically define the css class name
eklemek ve yerel tanm ad seeneinde temelde D. tanmlamak iin var. C. snf ad olarak.
it will automatically generate and assign.
Otomatik olarak retir ve atar.
This should take the original name,
Bu orijinal ad almaldr.
then two underscores, then the local name of the component and then a randomly generated hash with
Ardndan iki, bileenin yerel adn ve daha sonra rasgele oluturulmu karma satr
hash colon base 64:5.
kprck taban 64 kmr ve ate ile altizir.
This will generate these unique css class names which are then assigned automatically once we imported
Bu, bu benzersiz CSX snf adlarn retir ve bunlar o modlde size gsterdiim
them through that object from the css file as I showed you in that module.
gibi C S S dosyasndan bu nesne iinden aktardmzda otomatik olarak atanr.
Now copy these two lines with modules and localIdentName and go to the other webpack config file too,
imdi bu iki satr modller ve yerel idon adlaryla kopyalayn ve Weaver atmas Faltu'ya gidin.
this is the config file for the production build and of course there, we also want to ensure that we
her iki WePay yaplandrma dosyasnn da ayarlandn ve kaydedildiini.
can use css modules. So enter it here in the options, make sure to close that string here, enter it
retim yapm iin dosyay mahkum etmek ve elbette orada da caesuras modllerini kullanabilmemizi salamak istiyoruz, bylece
in the options for css loader so that both webpack config files have been adjusted and saved.
burada seenekleri girerseniz, DC'nin ykleyici olarak DC seeneklerine girdiiniz dizgeyi kapattndan emin olursunuz.
And with that, we got our project set up and we can get started.
Ve bunun zerine projemizi hazrladk ve balayabiliriz.
Now let's do some cleanup work,
imdi temizlik ii yapalm.
let's remove that logo.svg file which was created automatically, I don't need that and then the
Bu logoyu otomatik olarak oluturulan her dosyaya kaldralm l deilim
app.js file, we can get rid of the import of that file therefore. We can also clean up the app.js
ve sonra da dosyann ie aktarlmasndan kurtulabildiimiz iin de uygulamay temizleyebiliriz.
content here,
J. S. burada ierik.
remove the class name from the div and remove the app.css imports here even and remove the app.css file,
Snf adn lmden kaldrn ve burada D C S S ithalatn kaldrn ve dtke derin derinliini karn.
I don't need to style in here right now.
u anda burada stil yapmak zorunda deilim.
I will leave the global styling though
Geri global tarz brakacam.
but in the index.css file where I set up my global body style and which I still import normally in
Ancak endekslerde, genel vcut stilini ayarladm sonbaharda olduu gibi, dosyay referans alarak
quotation marks by referencing the file and not importing a classes object
ve bir Klaas'n nesnesini ie aktarmamakla, normalde trnak iine alyorum.
so therefore it will get applied globally. In that css file,
Dolaysyla dosya olarak genel dizinler uygulanacak.
I want to set the font family to another font. We could of course use that but I picked a different
Font ailesini bir dizi yaz tipi ile ayarlamak istiyorum, elbette adm atabilirdik, ancak biraz daha gzel
one which I find a bit more beautiful
bulduumuz farkl bir yaz tipi setim.
basically. I went to use open sans, and for that you can simply search for Google fonts and on the Google
yalnzca Google Forms'da arama yapabilirsin ve bahsettiiniz gibi Google fontlar sayfasnda bunun anlamn burada ayor.
fonts page as I just mentioned is the open sans font here.
Temel olarak ak anlamda kullanmaya baladm ve bunun iin
Now once you selected this, you can click on at the bottom to customize it and there
imdi bunu bir kez seerseniz, bunu alt ksmnda tklayarak zelletirebilirsiniz.
I don't just want to pick the regular one,
Normal olan semek istemiyorum sadece.
let's also pick up the bold one in case we need this,
Hepimize ihtiyacmz olursa diye cesur olan alalm.
in case we want to have some bold text, for example for headings.
rnein balklar iin cesur bir metin istiyorsanz.
Now with that, let's go to embed and there you find a link to the Google CDN from which you can import
imdi onunla ktye gidelim ve orada, Google CDN'ye bu fonu ithal edebileceiniz bir balant
this font
buluyorsunuz.
and this is perfectly fine, this is exactly the approach I want to use.
Ve bu mkemmel para cezas kullandmda tam olarak bu yaklam yapar.
So now with that link, let's go back to our project folder, to the public folder and to the index.html
imdi bu balantyla ortak klasre ve dizine html L5 projemiz klasre
file
dnelim.
and there I'll add it right above the title.
Ve hepsi baln hemen stnde eklendi.
Now speaking of the title, I'll also adjust this to my burger because well, this should be the name of my application
imdi konuan baln da benim burger iin de adalet nk bu burada benim bavuru ad
here.
olmal.
With that, the setup of the project is pretty much finished,
Bununla birlikte, proje seti olduka bitmi durumda.
we can now start writing our react application and implement that component tree we designed in the last
imdi yeniden uygulama bavurumuzu yazmaya balayabilir ve son derslerde tasarladmz bileenleri
lectures.
uygulayabiliriz.
So let's move on and start developing these components in the next lecture.
O halde devam edelim ve bir sonraki dersimizde bu bileenleri gelitirmeye balayalm.